加工海鲜怎么收费啊
How much do you charge for seafood processing?
一个元的几块
A few yuan per person.
一个元头的
Per head.
你们会不会换海鲜啊
Will you swap our fresh seafood for something else?
会
Yes, we will.
今天在广州南沙逛海鲜市场
Today we are exploring the seafood market in Nansha, Guangzhou.
看看仨人要花多少
Let's see how much it costs for the three of us.
这季节正好是珠江口
It's the perfect season at the Pearl River Estuary.
很多海鲜肥美的时候
A time when a lot of seafood is plump and delicious.
海鲜都在哪啊
Where is the seafood?
在这
Over here.
哦
Oh.
要不要
Do you want some?
三千的
These are 3,000.
这个是多少钱啊
How much is this?
五十块一块
50 yuan per piece.
有十二个的
There are twelve in total.
一块钱一只的是哪个呀
Which one is 1 yuan per piece?
一块钱到点套餐一起买的
The 1 yuan ones are part of a combo set.
这三个线有什么
What's in this three-item set?
单买就是一百五
It's 150 if bought separately.
然后加起来就是一百
But together it's only 100.
还要一斤多
And more than a catty extra.
多酥鸭
Duck with crispy skin.
还要那个白贝呀
And those white clams.
海草啊
Seaweed too.
全部鲜活的
All fresh and alive.
我总觉得哪里不对
I feel like something is not quite right.
你是不是把它标的高一点单买
Did you mark the single price higher on purpose?
这样显得套餐便宜一点
To make the combo set look cheaper?
对 没错
Yes, exactly.
我是不是揭露你了
Did I just expose you?
啊 没事没事
Ah, it's fine, no problem.
不是很正常
Isn't that normal?
来一百块钱吧
Let's get 100 yuan worth.
这样很好啊
This is very good.
带着不用撑就不是说嫌带着重
Easy to carry, not heavy at all.
很会做生意 再逛一下
You're good at business. Let's look around more.
酱麻棒15块钱一个
Snail sticks are 15 yuan each.
能摸吗
Can I touch them?
可以 关注你很久了
Sure, I've been following you for a long time.
所以那你肯定不会坑我是不是
So you definitely won't rip me off, right?
是啊
Of course not.
这个都是我的
These are all mine.
你帮我挑4个吧
Help me pick four.
60块
That's 60 yuan.
好
Okay.
50块卖不卖啊
Will you sell them for 50?
可以
Okay.
那40呢
What about 40?
那你上视频你就完蛋了
If you're in the video, you're doomed.
坏死你啊告诉你
I'm telling you, you'll be in trouble.
我就砍10块
I'm only bargaining for 10 yuan.
50块啊
50 yuan, then.
好
Okay.
我想买炒虾那些有吗
Do you have those stir-fried shrimps?
我看看
Let me see.
这个桥下就是天涯的
These shrimps are top quality.
我懂天涯
I know quality when I see it.
多少钱啊
How much are they?
75块
75 yuan.
买衣服应该多不多啊
Should we buy more?
不可以
No, that's enough.
你们这袋子都挺厚的啊
Your bags are quite thick.
我捶的一块钱袋子还在那边攒
I'm still saving that 1-yuan bag I bought.
哈哈哈哈
Hahaha.
18块
18 yuan.
好
Okay.
黄角丽有没有啊
Do you have yellowfin sea bream?
你去她的
Go to her stall.
四眼才能见到
Only professionals can spot them.
诶
Hey.
刘雨昕
Liu Yuxin!
诶 你好你好
Hey, hello, hello.
看来今天不用怕被坑了
Looks like I don't have to worry about being ripped off today.
黄角丽在前面并有
There's yellowfin sea bream up ahead.
我带你去吗
Shall I take you there?
这个是正宗古地的黄角丽
This is authentic local yellowfin sea bream.
当时都是半两半年生
They're all about six months old.
来 两条吧
Let's get two.
38块的
38 yuan.
他们默认出了个袋子的
They usually include a bag.
这边还有什么本地的
What other local specialties are here?
要不搞定这个
How about this one?
控肥鱼
Fatty fish.
现在是最好吃最肥的时候
Now is when they're the fattiest and most delicious.
这个35
This one is 35.
来一点
Get some.
18块
18 yuan.
你们这边人好多互相帮助啊
People here are so helpful to each other.
没事 都是邻居
It's nothing, we're all neighbors.
有那种水蟹吗
Do you have those water crabs?
我帮你拿
I'll get them for you.
他生意都不做了
He's not even attending to his own business.
人太好了
He's such a nice person.
哎 刘萍萍
Hey, Liu Pingping!
哎 哈喽哈喽
Hey, hello, hello.
水蟹没有肉
Water crabs have no meat.
就吸那个汁
You just suck the juices out.
对对对
Yes, exactly.
来 三个吧
Let's get three.
三个
Three.
就本地的海鲜都差不多了
The local seafood is mostly like this.
好像没在你店里买的
It seems I didn't buy anything from your stall.
没所谓的
It doesn't matter.
谢谢
Thank you.
这个叫黄蜜桃
This is called 'Yellow Peach' (local seafood name).
这个本地有
We have it locally.
15一斤
15 yuan per catty.
70块给你
I'll give it to you for 70.
来一点
Get some.
28 yuan.
你本人比照片好看很多
You look much better in person than in photos.
起码年轻10岁
At least ten years younger.
谢谢
Thank you.
哇 这个好东西
Wow, this is good stuff.
省蟑螂 比较浓湿
Very rich and flavorful.
这多少钱
How much is this?
28一斤
28 yuan per catty.
这么便宜
So cheap!
一两
Per tael (50g).
啊 一两
Oh, per tael.
200块一斤
That's 200 yuan per catty.
我们这边的配方就是
Our recipe here is...
如果月料非常多
If there are a lot of ingredients...
就是可以用来包它
We can use them to wrap it.
快点来一点吧
Let's get some quickly.
90块
90 yuan.
122元
122 yuan.
谢谢
Thank you.
买了这么多一共是420
We bought so much, total is 420 yuan.
我们找了一个离市场有点距离的地方加工
We found a place a bit further from the market for processing.
加工海鲜怎么收费啊
How much for seafood processing?
一个人10块 给人头的
10 yuan per person, per head.
包括什么做法呢
What cooking methods are included?
蒸 白炒 煎 加烧 10块
Steaming, stir-frying, pan-frying, all for 10 yuan.
炸 干 洗五
Deep-frying, drying, and cleaning.
把它投餐就两块
Just 2 yuan extra for the set.
哦 这个虾
Oh, these shrimps.
这个白炒
Stir-fry these.
那不用额外花钱了
Then no extra money needed.
这个是水蟹
These are water crabs.
草啊
Seaweed.
做粥可不可以啊
Can we make congee with these?
不做啊
No, we don't.
哈哈哈哈
Hahaha.
这个蒸的可以
These can be steamed.
黄角粒啊
Yellowfin sea bream.
蒸 拿这个生蒸
Steam these fresh.
拿这个生蒸
这个排骨
These ribs.
你这买多少都是按人头收
No matter how much you buy, it's per head.
你们会不会换海鲜啊
Will you swap our fresh seafood?
嘿 我们这面20年了
Hey, we've been here for 20 years.
我的面海鲜
Our seafood is authentic.
这就夫妻店
This is a mom-and-pop shop.
就叔叔阿姨两个人
Just the uncle and aunt running it.
白灼的炒虾蘸点酱油
Boiled shrimps dipped in soy sauce.
真的很甜
It's really sweet.
皮很薄
The skin is very thin.
本店说这个是叉王
The shop says these are top tier.